# Nathaniel Acker

Toronto, ON L4J 7R8 • nacker999@gmail.com • 416-319-9144 • linkedin.com/in/nathaniel-acker • https://github.com/N-acker

#### **Summary**

**Computer Science** graduate from York University with experience in JavaScript, Node. JS, Java, Flutter, C, Bash, Python, SQL, Neo4J and MongoDB. Analytical, goal-oriented, and creative problem-solver with enthusiasm for working with new technologies. Committed to making a valuable contribution to any organization.

#### **Skills**

- · Object-Oriented Programming
- · Computational Thinking
- · Data Structure use and creation
- · Software Design
- Excellent communication
- · Collaborative team member

#### **Education**

BSc, Bachelor of Science: Computer Science, Lassonde School of Engineering, Toronto, ON

**Expected graduation in 2024** 

Software Tools:

- Java Script ( JQuery and React libraries) & Node.JS
- HTML & CSS
- MongoDB, Neo4J and SQL

- Advanced Object-Oriented Programming
- C Language & Shell Programming
- Python

#### Projects:

- Created functioning website with single and multiplayer rock-paper-scissors game
- Developed fully functioning android app that contains number guessing game
- Implemented a Java backend model where REST API endpoints are supported by Ne04i graph databases

Juno College: Web Development (HTML & CSS), JavaScript (JQuery), Juno College, Toronto ON

2021

#### Projects:

- Created fully functional strikingly appealing web page using HTML and CSS
- Developed a webpage allowing users to search movies which are pulled using an API from a movie database using the jQuery

BSc, Bachelor of Science: Biology, York University, Toronto, ON

2020

### **Experience**

Web Developer, STEM FellowShip - Toronto, ON, Canada

07/2023 - 02/2024

- · Worked primarily with WordPress, HTML, and Firebase
- Maintained website with minor changes as requested by board members
- Created large-scale changes including new webpages and structural adjustments

## Software Developer (Internship), Samme - Tel Aviv, Israel

05/2022 - 07/2022

- Developed software features for Samme chrome extension using Dart under Flutter UI for frontend and Node.JS for backend
- · Applied and utilized OpenAI library in Samme chrome extension to generate appropriate responses for clients
- Planned and followed through with weekly routine using Scrum methodology; documented weekly tasks and design changes using Jira as well as Notion; merged oncoming changes for future version releases using GitHub

#### Content Moderator, Majorel - Waterloo, ON, Canada

06/2021 - 05/2022

- Evaluated online social media & advertising content in conjunction with policy
- · Examined content which included ad units, applications and web pages; recorded findings using web-based tools & workflow systems
- Delivered optimal quality and productivity levels through data analysis